<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on nickforr</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on nickforr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Iliad</title>
      <link>/2017/10/24/tidy-iliad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/24/tidy-iliad/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by yet another @hrbrmstr project, I thought I’d have a go at replicating his approach for assessing the sentiment of a book, but using Homer’s Iliad. (I know, it’s not Christmas-y but hey ho ho ho).
library(hrbrthemes) library(stringi) library(tidytext) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ──────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 2.2.1 ✔ purrr 0.2.4 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.4 ## ✔ tidyr 0.8.0 ✔ stringr 1.3.0 ## ✔ readr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainfall</title>
      <link>/2017/07/12/rainfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/12/rainfall/</guid>
      <description>Wetter in the West (of Scotland)? I grew up in Fife and now live on the outskirts of Glasgow. And maybe it’s just the ‘lovely’ July weather we’ve been experiencing, or maybe it’s just that I’m getting older and have a selective memory for the past, but I don’t recall summers being quite so wet when I was growing up!
I thought I’d take the opportunity to explore the data and play around with some visualisation…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loopy annuities</title>
      <link>/2017/07/06/loopy-annuities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/06/loopy-annuities/</guid>
      <description>I was tidying up some R code that involved some ‘looping’ and wondered whether the approach I’d taken could be improved uppon (I’d had nagging doubts over the approach but it worked and seemed fast enough, so hadn’t bothered refactoring it until now).
Background is that at work we use a lot of monte carlo simulations through economic scenario generators [https://www.actuaries.org.uk/learn-develop/attend-event/economic-scenario-generators] and so are dealing with matrices with dimensions representing timesteps (for projecting, for example, interest rates) and simulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out blogdown</title>
      <link>/2017/05/24/trying-out-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/24/trying-out-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is just a quick check to see if I can easily add posts to this blog using blogdown.
With a lack of imagination, I’m using the mtcars data set and ggplot (via tidyverse) to check it’s working ok (using viridis for colours).
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>